<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thiago B. Procaci</title>
    <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thiago B. Procaci</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>YouTube thumbnail classification using PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/thumbnail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/thumbnail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a step-by-step of how to classify thumbnail images with deep learning models using PyTorch library. All references to Python code (classes, method) can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thiagoprocaci/thumbnail-classification&#34;&gt;this GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;problem&#34;&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Given two youtube channels, what &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/What-is-a-YouTube-thumbnail&#34;&gt;thumbnail&lt;/a&gt; corresponds to each channel?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is a problem of image classification.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We choose two YouTube channels to perform this classification: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/nerdologia&#34;&gt;Nerdologia&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/CanalPeixeBabel&#34;&gt;Peixe Babel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;downloading-thumbnails&#34;&gt;Downloading Thumbnails&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are going to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network&#34;&gt;CNN (convolutional neural network)&lt;/a&gt; to solve the problem.&#xA;The first task that we need to do is to download all thumbnails before starting building the machine learning model.&#xA;This task is performed by the class YouTubeCrawler. We use pyyoutube library to access YouTube videos through an API.&#xA;Besides, to do the download, you must generate the YouTube API key. See this &lt;a href=&#34;https://console.developers.google.com/apis/credentials&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to get details about the API key.&#xA;Then, paste your key in the constructor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thiagoprocaci/thumbnail-classification/blob/main/src/YouTubeThumbnail.py&#34;&gt;YouTubeCrawler class&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shakespeare&#39;s Wisdom for the Digital Age: Polonius&#39; Advice Revisited</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/hamlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/hamlet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Polonius and Laertes are characters in Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s Hamlet. I encourage the study of classics such as Hamlet since we have a lot to learn from them. The play is a tragedy, set in Denmark, where Prince Hamlet seeks to avenge the death of his father who was murdered by his brother Claudius. Afterwards, Claudius became the king. The plot is about this regicide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Polonius was the silly man of the kingdom (tedious old fool as described by Prince Hamlet) and the chief counselor of Claudius. Laertes, his son, is leaving for France. In this scene, Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s ability appears in Polonius&amp;rsquo;s advice to Laertes before his departure. In other words, Shakespeare surprises us when he makes wise words come from the silliest person in the kingdom. The advice can be divided into 8 recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Science: trend, applicability and new data</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/datascience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been involved in data science projects as never before.&#xA;Data science is a trend. Saying that someone is a data scientist sounds nice, but few know what they actually do. My experience tells me that applying techniques is quite easy, even in the data science field. The challenge is to find a problem that a technique solves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back to the beginning, why am I asked to solve issues through data science? Regardless of my background, which might suggest that my principal tool is always data science methods, the problem should come first instead of a data science solution. After a deeper investigation of the problem, I could say if it is related to data science. Such confusion might be because of the imprecise definition of terms such as data science or data scientist. For instance, a common definition of data scientist is the professional who has expertise in computer science, statistics, and artificial intelligence. This lack of definition can be the reason for such confusion. Another issue is the marketing involved, which may explain why someone wants data science solutions. Data science is at the peak of expectations, and announcing that a company provides data science solutions is a marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lifelong learner</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/lifelonglearner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/lifelonglearner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of us describe ourselves by applying labels that shape our identity. Someone says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a musician&amp;rdquo;, and this behavior gives them a sense of belonging, feeling connected to a group. Others prefer to describe themselves by their characteristics, hobbies, or lifestyle—such as vegetarians, extroverts, gamers, or easygoing people. Each label indicates a set of habits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zygmunt Bauman, a sociologist who described the world from a fascinating perspective, says that we live in liquid modernity, in which everything changes quickly and nothing is made to last. Every day, new content is created and knowledge grows fast. Yuval Harari, the author of Homo Deus, states that we are the first generation that does not know what to teach future generations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovation and Invention</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working as a software developer for a long time and I usually hear my coworkers make arguments like &amp;ldquo;our company needs to innovate&amp;rdquo;. However, when you talk about innovation in a company, you will see people coming up with ideas such as technology adoption or the usage of a new cool methodology to create or improve something.&#xA;Everybody agrees that it is good to create new things and some people feel proud of their creation. However, innovation is not just a creation or a simple improvement. It is a more complex process.&#xA;In this text, I would like to discuss innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
