<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thiago B. Procaci</title>
    <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thiago B. Procaci</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Polonius&#39; advice to Laertes and the contemporary world</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/hamlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/hamlet/</guid>
      <description>Polonius and Laertes are characters in Shakespeare&amp;rsquo;s Hamlet. I encourage the study of classics such as Hamlet since we have a lot to learn from them. The play is a tragedy, set in Denmark, where Prince Hamlet seeks to avenge the death of his father who was murdered by his brother Claudius. Afterward, Claudius became the king. The plot is about this regicide.
Polonius was the silly man of the kingdom (tedious old fool as described by Prince Hamlet) and the chief counselor of Claudius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science: trend, applicability and new data</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/datascience/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I have been involved in data science projects as never before. Data science is a trend. Saying that someone is data scientist is nice but few know what (s)he actually does. My experience tells that applying techniques quite easy, even in the data science field. The challenge is to find a problem that a technique solves.
Back to the beginning, why am I asked to solve issues through data science?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifelong learner</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/lifelonglearner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/lifelonglearner/</guid>
      <description>Many of us describe ourselves applying labels that shape our identity. Someone says, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a musician&amp;rdquo;, and this behavior gives him a sense of belonging, feeling connected to a group. Others prefer to describe themselves by their characteristics, hobbies or lifestyle such as vegetarians, extroverts, gamer, easygoing. Each label indicates a set of habits.
Zygmunt Bauman, a sociologist who described the world from a fascinating perspective, says that we live in the liquid modernity in which everything changes quickly and nothing is done to last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Skills Thiago is a data scientist and a senior software developer. His main skills are:
 Agile Software Development Social Network Analysis Applied Statistics Machine Learning  International Publications  How Do Outstanding Users Differ From Other Users in Q&amp;amp;A Communities? (2019) Trust Investigation in Communities Using Feature Learning (2019) Learning in Communities: How Do Outstanding Users Differ From Other Users? (2018) Experts and likely to be closed discussions in question and answer communities: An analytical overview (2018) Modelling Experts Behaviour in Q&amp;amp;A Communities to Predict Worthy Discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation and Invention</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/innovation/</guid>
      <description>I have been working as a software developer for a long time and I usually listen to my coworkers’ opinions using arguments like “our company needs to innovate”. However, when you talk about innovation in a company, you will see people coming up with ideas such as technology adoption or the usage of a new cool methodology to create or improve something. Everybody agrees that it is good to create new things and some people feel proud of their creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday to BM</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/zone/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/zone/3/</guid>
      <description>A scholarship A letter from my email says that I have got a scholarship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday to BM</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/zone/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/zone/1/</guid>
      <description>Happy Birthday to BM! Happy Birthday to you, Be happy and healthy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I got my first salary</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/zone/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/zone/2/</guid>
      <description>I got my first salary In this semester, I am a TA for C Language Programming. Today I got my first salary in my life. I felt proud of myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gallery</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/gallery/a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/gallery/a/</guid>
      <description>  /img/index.png     /img/list.png     /img/single.png     /img/zone.png     /img/about.png   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>