<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Scientist on Thiago B. Procaci</title>
    <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/tags/data-scientist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Scientist on Thiago B. Procaci</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/tags/data-scientist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Science: trend, applicability and new data</title>
      <link>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thiagoprocaci.github.io/post/datascience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been involved in data science projects as never before.&#xA;Data science is a trend. Saying that someone is a data scientist sounds nice, but few know what they actually do. My experience tells me that applying techniques is quite easy, even in the data science field. The challenge is to find a problem that a technique solves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Back to the beginning, why am I asked to solve issues through data science? Regardless of my background, which might suggest that my principal tool is always data science methods, the problem should come first instead of a data science solution. After a deeper investigation of the problem, I could say if it is related to data science. Such confusion might be because of the imprecise definition of terms such as data science or data scientist. For instance, a common definition of data scientist is the professional who has expertise in computer science, statistics, and artificial intelligence. This lack of definition can be the reason for such confusion. Another issue is the marketing involved, which may explain why someone wants data science solutions. Data science is at the peak of expectations, and announcing that a company provides data science solutions is a marketing strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
